In the 2026.0 version, we have generously introduced a new band-aid wearing tool.
Today we will demonstrate for you how to effectively and conveniently make wearing effects for number 1 and other items.
In the past, the simulation band-aid through the hole eye is often a manual operation that is often used.
By using a new band-aid wearing tool, you only need to select the hole eye once.
The system can automatically plan the band-aid insert path and direction.
The tool can not only create a path, but also create a completely editable 2D version.
This greatly shortens your production time and increases design efficiency.
Next, we will use this as an example to explain the specific operation process of the tool for you in detail.
The first step is to define the thread path.
First, let's define the band-aid insert path.
From the 2D tool bar,
select the band-aid wearing tool.
In the 2D window,
press the first hole eye where the band-aid is inserted or inserted.
Follow the expected thread path.
Press the remaining hole eye.
After selecting the last hole eye,
double-click the left mouse button or press the return button to complete the path setting.
After the setting is complete,
you will see the automatically generated band-aid version in the 2D window.
You can freely edit the version.
The second step is to select and fine-tune the settings and details.
After the path setting is complete,
you can take a step further and fine-tune the band-aid insert path and curve to achieve the best visual effect.
First, let's take a look at the reverse direction.
After the path setting is complete,
the mouse icon will automatically turn into a reverse icon.
At this time, click the specific hole eye.
You can turn the band-aid in the direction of the insert.
For example, change from top to bottom to bottom to top to bottom.
The relevant adjustment will be implemented in the 3D window.
Next, let's take a look at the adjustment of the bend rate.
By adjusting the bend rate of the slide,
you can change the curve of the band-aid,
and increase the bend rate appropriately.
It can effectively prevent the band-aid plate and surrounding plates from collision or wear,
thereby ensuring the stability of subsequent simulation.
Next, let's take a look at the material properties.
The automatically generated band-aid plate
is the physical property of the fabric.
You can handle it like a regular clothing board.
You can freely adjust its thickness in the attribute editor.
The material and physical properties.
Next, I will provide you with a few professional skills to improve the simulation stability.
When you need to tighten the band-aid,
before starting the simulation,
you can freeze all the plates other than the band-aid.
Right-click on the blank area of the 3D window.
Then select the simulation property.
Increase the bend rate of the bend rate to 0.1.
The bend rate of the bend rate is only to maintain the thickness of the plate collision,
but to increase the maintenance force.
Increase this value can ensure that when tightening the band-aid,
the band-aid will not bounce out of the hole.
Next, we can increase the length of the two ends of the band-aid
by adding two fixed pins.
This is to prevent the two ends of the band-aid from falling out of the hole
after the simulation.
And you can adjust the width of the band-aid plate
in the 2D window.
Finally, before running the simulation,
it is recommended to apply the hardening function to the band-aid plate.
This makes the shape more solid.
Now let's run the simulation and tighten the band-aid.
After tightening the band-aid plate,
the band-aid plate will naturally fall off.
Replace the band-aid material.
That's all.
You can use this tool to create a more diversified band-aid effect.
Next, I will show you three different band-aid effects.
In this example, I used the
two fixed pins.
The first one is to make a band-aid part.
This is to accelerate the band-aid.
The second type of band-aid you can do is
to see if the band-aid is tight enough.
Here we go.
From now on, even if you face the most complicated binding structure, you only need to simply click and tweak the parameters several times, and you can easily fix it.
We look forward to your use of this efficient new function to create more amazing 3D works.